

With over three years of experience in developing innovative IoT, data and digitalization solutions, I have extensive know-how. I have mastered waterfall model, agile methods and

the DevOps process to successfully implement projects. I attach great importance to developing together with the company, using new technologies and implementing innovative digitalization products.

About Me

Michael Bieri

Grotweg 23 2543 Lengnau BE +41774130839 michael.bieri@hotmail.com 13.03.1992

https://github.com/MichaelBieri





Work Experience

03/2021 - 06/2024	Junior Electro Engineer LAUFEN Bathrooms AG, Laufen Development and management of soft- and hardware projects with focus on requirement engineering
09/2018 - 02/2021	Junior Project Manager Amstein + Walthert Basel AG, Basel Engineering in building technology/automation
07/2018 - 09/2018	Engineering Internship Kappeler Infra Consult AG, Laufen
11/2013 - 07/2014	Workshop and Construction Internship F. Hoffmann-La-Roche AG, Basel
11/2010 - 05/2011	Trust Internship TVR Treuhand GmbH, Basel
09/2009 - 10/2009	Bank Internship WIR Bank, Basel
Education	



02/2024 - 08/2024	CAS Data Science Fundamentals Swiss Distance University of Applied Sciences FFHS
09/2019 - 04/2022	MAS Automation Management University of Applied Sciences Northwestern Switzerland FHNW
09/2014 - 05/2018	BSc Energy- and Environment Technology University of Applied Sciences Northwestern Switzerland FHNW
08/2011 - 08/2012	High School Diploma Schulen kvBL, Liestal
08/2007 - 08/2010	Business Diploma Business school kvBL, Reinach BL



PROBLEM-SOLVING

COMMUNICATION

Soft Skills

AGILE MANAGEMENT

REQUIREMENT ENGINEERING

STATISTICS

DATA VISUALIZATION

DATA WRANGLING

PROGRAMMING

MACHINE LEARNING

Languages

German Mother tongue English C1 French В2